[{"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944b", "question": "In what Arizona city does the movie \"Psycho\" begin?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f169bbf7c52aae91cc07d4", "question": "Who played \"Hawkeye\" in the 1970 film \"MASH\"?", "answer": "Donald Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decf57ea2747c8aff16d1d", "question": "Junko Tabei was the first woman to reach what?", "answer": "Summit of Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338873", "question": "What mid-day nap takes its name from the Spanish word sexta, meaning sixth?", "answer": "The siesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d9", "question": "What city boasted the world's first subway line?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91c", "question": "In 1968, what became a required part of the automobile's safety equipment in the US?", "answer": "The seat belt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37b", "question": "Who conquered the Matterhorn in 1865?", "answer": "Edward Whymper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015de7afe83fe1f2a824b6b", "question": "What military leader spread Greek culture from his native Macedonia to the Indian subcontinent?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab93", "question": "What year did Cambodia declare its independence from France?", "answer": "1953", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd822ccd0de9af39e9d46ab", "question": "What is said to be the first table top game to exist?", "answer": "Dice", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339631", "question": "What city was the setting for the 1994 movie \"Miracle on 34th Street\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b40d01dd7bf43be5e7ba", "question": "Where was the first known fried chicken recipe published?", "answer": "The United Kingdom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc4dd6ce05a3942286f38", "question": "What is the name of the fishing boat that is featured in the film \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Andrea Gail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dd97f4f3bc4a292f8622", "question": "\"Operation Overlord\" was the code name for the invasion of what country during World War II?", "answer": "German-occupied France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990f8befa5fdd6dd25324f1", "question": "Where is Queen Maud Land located?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8b", "question": "Which US president survived two assassination attempts during the 20th century?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ba", "question": "In the movie industry, what does a Gaffer do?", "answer": "Design and execution of lighting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d62", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Cegg?", "answer": "Allison Janney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339731", "question": "Audrey Hepburn was born in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfe229dc5ec6cd98a8328", "question": "Who is the protagonist of \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "Katniss Everdeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a288", "question": "\"Next\" and \"Paycheck\" are films based on stories by which science-fiction author?", "answer": "Philip K. Dick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be3c", "question": "How many on-field players are there in a standard Australian rules football team?", "answer": "Eighteen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea438bff048f679a45ab82", "question": "What is the inherent voltage of lithium?", "answer": "2.7 volts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c702", "question": "What planet is named for the Roman equivalent of the Greek god Zeus?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad3", "question": "In computing, the term \"bit\" is an abbreviation of what?", "answer": "Binary Digit\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded1f4ea2747c8aff16d38", "question": "Laliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speaking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f35", "question": "Who titled his 1989 autobiography \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff13fb0b0ee8c595b6d3991", "question": "What famous author was known for his love of cats with extra toes?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b275", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea49d6ff048f679a45abbc", "question": "What part of the plant gets water and nutrients to the rest of the plant?", "answer": "Stem", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be42", "question": "What sports team used the Swinging Friar as its team emblem until 1984?", "answer": "The San Diego Padres", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c85dfbde8045e48466d7", "question": "What is Johannes Kepler best known for?", "answer": "Kepler's laws of planetary motion are three scientific laws describing the motion of planets around the Sun.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ec49fe83fe1f2a824bfe", "question": "In the United States, 1 May is officially recognized as Loyalty Day. Which American President instituted this holiday?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab56", "question": "What is the largest country in South America?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ea15fe83fe1f2a824bec", "question": "The first time someone bought something with bitcoins, 10,000 of them were exchanged for what?", "answer": "Two pizzas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7e65ff048f679a45ac0d", "question": "Barophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e0", "question": "What fruit comes in Eureka and Meyer variety?", "answer": "Lemons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2f64f032c0db195b488", "question": "What charter did a group of English barons force King John to sign in 1215 at Runnymede?", "answer": "Magna Carta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb357612627b8fe95581be3", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec881aec223966ae8f881b", "question": "Blondie of the film \"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "\"the Man with No Name\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe905b301dd7bf43be5e87f", "question": "Surprisingly, whose team lost a Christmas-decorating contest when she was an inmate at Alderson, a West Virginia women\u2019s prison?", "answer": "Margaret Stewart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ea", "question": "Which Hollywood film studio's logo is a mountain surrounded by 22 stars?", "answer": "Paramount", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95b2ca55722f97b22684df", "question": "What color was Obi-Wan Kenobi's Lightsaber?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0f", "question": "What was Wayne Gretzky's jersey number during his professional hockey career?", "answer": "99", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe2", "question": "According to the TV series, how many stories are there in \"The Naked City\"?", "answer": "Eight million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c408877e98cb97778999", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Africa?", "answer": "Tugela Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c198", "question": "In what sort of landscape would you find an erg?", "answer": "Desert", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af78", "question": "Which US president is buried in Mount Vernon, Virginia?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f79", "question": "What was Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e3d4fe83fe1f2a824bab", "question": "What was the significance of Mt. Suribachi?", "answer": "It was the site of a major battle on Iwo Jima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5a", "question": "Who was Germany's first female chancellor?", "answer": "Angela Merkel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1c0aff497e33de805791d", "question": "What three teams did Babe Ruth play for?", "answer": "Boston Red Sox, New York Yankees, Boston Braves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character is allergic to regular milk?", "answer": "Milhouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec23308dc25ca9e12ef62e", "question": "What color does a chameleon turn when its trying to warm up?", "answer": "Black", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339579", "question": "In A Christmas Carol what song is sung outside of Scrooge's office?", "answer": "God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012153c63c99d48cd169ae8", "question": "Which country offered Einstein the presidency?", "answer": "Israel -- Einstein declined, saying he lacked enough of both \"natural aptitude\" and \"experience\" for the role.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a514", "question": "Which is the largest desert in Australia?", "answer": "Great Victoria Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdab3320b8cce1e6fda7043", "question": "What common animal is constitutionally protected in Florida?", "answer": "Pigs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd9725723c87fd04dd15e52", "question": "In which country was the umbrella invented?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067ecaff9c0647b50a807e", "question": "To what age did the US state of Hawaii change the legal smoking age on January 1, 2016?", "answer": "21", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8d", "question": "Francis Scott Key wrote what famous song?", "answer": "The Star Spangled Banner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe5230b1bf59ab7d2e380ed", "question": "In cooking what would you use a \"dredger\" for?", "answer": "To sprinkle flour or sugar lightly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c1", "question": "Who was the first figure skater to appear on a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Kristi Yamaguchi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f8", "question": "What was the subtitle of the 2005 movie \"Miss Congeniality 2\"?", "answer": "Armed and Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf2", "question": "In which city was the composer Ludwig Van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a621", "question": "Which US state was named after a president?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cf", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Volga river?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a5", "question": "What nation was led by Peter the Great?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb63c7e83c707845b2125", "question": "What is a hybrid of a cow and bison called?", "answer": "Beefalo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff9", "question": "What does a bibliophobe fear, or hate?", "answer": "Books", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cb", "question": "What actor played Bill Murray's love interest in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "Andie MacDowell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589e25db0d66a186cb54f", "question": "French fries are claimed to have originated in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3fe", "question": "In land area, what is the largest country in South America?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bae", "question": "What was the last name of the main family on the TV show \"3rd Rock From the Sun\"?", "answer": "Solomon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac5e", "question": "Who is said to have been presented to Julius Caesar in a carpet?", "answer": "Cleopatra", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5937eed608d98002fdd633d9", "question": "From which musical did \"One Night in Bangkok Makes a Hard Man Humble\" and \"I Know Him So Well\" come?", "answer": "Chess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a059", "question": "\"Run\" is a 1994 Hong Kong remake of which shoe string-budget action film by Robert Rodriguez?", "answer": "El Mariachi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9a22596a59cbdfbd3c8", "question": "In many Old West cities, the colorful phrase \"Boot Hill\" referred to what?", "answer": "Cemetery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c8", "question": "In 1980, what executed man was added to the Anglican Church's calendar of saint?", "answer": "Sir Thomas More", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f81701dd7bf43be5e83f", "question": "Ophidiophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c4dafbde8045e48466a3", "question": "Which animal\u2019s name translates as \"river horse\" in Greek?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- From the\u00a0ancient Greek\u00a0(\u1f31\u03c0\u03c0\u03bf\u03c0\u03cc\u03c4\u03b1\u03bc\u03bf\u03c2), hippos spend a lot of their daylight hours in rivers and lakes to keep cool.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db78230ab2c8f322317ff2", "question": "Which author wrote about the Cornish seaside boarding school Malory Towers?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe52bc11bf59ab7d2e38104", "question": "With what skill did Odysseus defeat Penelope\u2019s suitors?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c283", "question": "How often are brain cells replaced?", "answer": "Never", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c672", "question": "What mission was the first successful manned mission to land on the Moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f939fa5fdd6dd25324f5", "question": "What film did John Wayne win his only Oscar for?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370cb1381754895396385", "question": "The Blondie song \"Call Me\" is featured in what movie?", "answer": "\"American Gigolo\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339851", "question": "In \"Spirited Away\", the workers that feed coal to the boiler furnace are made from what?", "answer": "Soot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892a", "question": "In Larry Niven's novel \"Ringworld\", what is the drug that extends human life to near immortality?", "answer": "Boosterspice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989abd6cb8751d53e7d7607", "question": "What is the \"nogada\" in the Mexican dish \"Chiles en nogada\"?", "answer": "Walnut based cream sauce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0d", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Quickening\"?", "answer": "Highlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa4102c73aa70ea0b70b0e", "question": "What tiny island makes the curling stones used in the Olympics?", "answer": "Ailsa Craig, Scotland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe7", "question": "How many players are in a Polo team?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb58155dad637d903c880e", "question": "Venice's famed Bridge of Sighs connects two what?", "answer": "Prisons -- The bridge connects an old prison inside the Doge's Palace to a newer one across the Rio di Palazzo.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa566cc73aa70ea0b70b2b", "question": "Which country hosts the World Ice Golf Championship?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909cabdbb53d1af658864d2", "question": "On what short story was the 1946 film \"It\u2019s a Wonderful Life\" based on?", "answer": "The Greatest Gift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab28", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba6", "question": "How many suspects are there in a game of \"Clue\"?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffcfd1cf6db9ac4808d07", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sydney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd22bec223966ae8f88c3", "question": "What board game do the three fairies play in \"Maleficent\"?", "answer": "Nine men's morris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989a8a3cb8751d53e7d75fc", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3dc444f0f6af5b06663f", "question": "Andorra la Vella is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36c", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is the first air sign of the calender year?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c8e49076251badbead7", "question": "What was the name of the space capsule that carried the first woman in space?", "answer": "Vostok 6 -- It carried Soviet cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova in space on 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba0", "question": "Barry Allen was the alter ego of which comic book superhero?", "answer": "The Flash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc7", "question": "What band based its hit \"China in Your Hand\" on Mary Shelley's \"Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "T'Pau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca83", "question": "Which scientist is credited with inventing margarine?", "answer": "Hippolyte Mege-Mouries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feb33dd7e83c707845b20c6", "question": "During the US civil rights movement in the 1960s, who said: \"We declare our right on this earth\u2026to be a human being\u2026by any means necessary\"?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be02", "question": "What is another name for a \"numismatist\"?", "answer": "Coin collector", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0d", "question": "Who was Anne of Green Gables' best friend?", "answer": "Diana Barry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59d1850d3b17032616b590fb", "question": "What 14th century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "Piers Plowman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339290", "question": "On the TV show \"Lost\", what group conducts scientific experiments on the island?", "answer": "Dharma Initiative", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d70", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Space Odyssey\"?", "answer": "2001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ba", "question": "What actor played the role of Officer Don Orville in the TV show \"Third Rock From The Sun\"?", "answer": "Wayne Knight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a259", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock die?", "answer": "1980", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636c4c967692ea851899a9", "question": "What beer brand shares a name with one of the Founding Father of the United States?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b678", "question": "A \"top-sider\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Shoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e1", "question": "What year was Ben Jonson's \"The Alchemist\" first performed?", "answer": "1610", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97a", "question": "The North Star is also known as?", "answer": "Polaris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0a", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Edge of Reason\"?", "answer": "Bridget Jones's Diary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ae", "question": "The first spin-off of C.S.I., starting in 2002, was set in what city?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c80dfbde8045e48466cd", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339364", "question": "What was Mary's last name on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ad", "question": "What baseball hall-of-famer was nicknamed \"Hammerin' Hank\"?", "answer": "Hank Aaron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b309", "question": "Who was found in a \"spider hole\" on December 13, 2003?", "answer": "Saddam Hussein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b69920de762b54eb9be941f", "question": "Who released the album \"The 20/20 Experience\" in 2013?", "answer": "Justin Timberlake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bd849076251badbeac9", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a955961d1b4d384d5d678", "question": "Which fruit is affected by a grey type of fungus known commonly as Noble Rot?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339403", "question": "Who played Al Pacino's attorney in the 1993 movie \"Carlito's Way\"?", "answer": "Sean Penn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb59", "question": "What was the nickname of professional boxing champion Thomas Hearns?", "answer": "Hitman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f80", "question": "What was Robyn Hitchcock's backing band?", "answer": "The Egyptians", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4e", "question": "What modern day country is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69e6620565ad31a57c783", "question": "Benito Mussolini died by what method?", "answer": "He was shot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a4", "question": "What is poliosis?", "answer": "Graying of hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339695", "question": "Who starred as Achilles in the 2004 movie \"Troy\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf9", "question": "N'Djamena is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca2", "question": "Which organization manages Stonehenge?", "answer": "English Heritage", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e604fe83fe1f2a824bc8", "question": "Whose body was exhumed from Westminster Abbey, more than two years after his death, to be \"executed\" for treason?", "answer": "Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b92", "question": "What wealthy comic-book title character keeps his mansion tidy with the help of a robot maid, Irona?", "answer": "Richie Rich", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa93", "question": "Halifax is the capital of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Nova Scotia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bfe0877e98cb9777896b", "question": "What country borders the Caspian Sea, Persian Gulf, and Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3a63ff048f679a45ab2b", "question": "What does the human lacrimal gland produce?", "answer": "Tears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5de", "question": "Saginaw Bay opens into what body of water?", "answer": "Lake Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c401", "question": "A male horse is known as a colt until it reaches what age?", "answer": "Five", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf05", "question": "What large red flower is the floral emblem of New South Wales?", "answer": "Waratah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf8", "question": "In which movie did Neve Campbell portray a witch?", "answer": "The Craft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339911", "question": "What blues legend sings with U2 on the song \"When Love Comes to Town\"?", "answer": "B.B. King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597de01177980686f722d188", "question": "The word \"Sandwich\" is a reference to which 18th century English aristocrat?", "answer": "John Montagu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ad", "question": "How many wings does a butterfly have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96ec023c87fd04dd15e3c", "question": "When was the first commercial film screening?", "answer": "1895", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f9", "question": "For whom is Hadassah, the Jewish women's organization, named?", "answer": "Esther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a244", "question": "In what film does the HAL 9000 appear?", "answer": "2001: A Space Odyssey\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c55", "question": "What historical event is central to the novel \u201cA Tale of Two Cities\u201d?", "answer": "The French Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07c", "question": "In which sport would you expect to find a Short Stop?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0afcae662d71a53650fc3", "question": "Who is Fridwulfa the mother of?", "answer": "Rubeus Hagrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb13", "question": "Often worn by young girls, \"Mary Janes\" are what type of fashion item?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1e", "question": "What period preceded Picasso's \"Rose Period\"?", "answer": "Blue Period", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f3052145aa2bc17b61b2ac8", "question": "Chisinau is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Moldova", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29d", "question": "What US president loved Fresca so much he had a soda tap installed for the Oval Office?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339052", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Cry, the Beloved Country\"?", "answer": "Alan Paton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa3c773838c5c8a417f21", "question": "In 1612, who became the first person to observe Neptune?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei - However, he thought he was observing a star and not a planet.  Therefore, he did not receive credit for discovering the planet.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69d1020565ad31a57c774", "question": "Which U.S. president officially gave the White House its name?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6fcda9e54d890926f6d3", "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?", "answer": "Chile -- Ushuaia, Argentina held the title until 2019, when Chilean authorities upgraded the town Puerto Williams to city status.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c47", "question": "What ventriloquist was best known for his dummy Charlie McCarthy?", "answer": "Edgar Bergen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e7", "question": "When did actor W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaad87e83c707845b20e2", "question": "Who created the centigrade scale, which was later renamed in his honor?", "answer": "Anders Celsius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1e", "question": "What food company is listed on the New York Stock Exchange with the single letter \"K\"?", "answer": "Kellogg's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59220151a4edfd43a087adda", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Dreams From My Father\"?", "answer": "Barack Obama's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cea", "question": "What singer took his stage name from a Dublin hearing aid billboard?", "answer": "Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca28", "question": "What is the name of the instrument used for listening to the heart?", "answer": "Stethoscope\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0d", "question": "What author wore a trademark dyed-green carnation in his lapel in 1890s London?", "answer": "Oscar Wilde", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc04", "question": "The correction fluid Liquid Paper was invented in what year?", "answer": "1951", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945e", "question": "In the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\", who keeps are razor blade in his boot?", "answer": "Mr. Blonde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b4a6e662d71a53650fed", "question": "Which Dutch artist painted \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?", "answer": "Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a78e20565ad31a57c7ea", "question": "Which US President was known as \"The American Cincinnatus\"?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c189", "question": "Who was born Mark Feld?", "answer": "Marc Bolan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907e", "question": "Who is the subject of the book \"Longitude\" by Dava Sobel?", "answer": "John Harrison", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f5", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Superfly\"?", "answer": "Curtis Mayfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc8816de0eb824d4052fc", "question": "What is Camp David's official name?", "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecdb56ec223966ae8f88f3", "question": "In \"Die Hard,\" how does John McClane signal officer Powell that something is wrong at Nakatomi Plaza?", "answer": "Drops a dead body on his car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989aec8cb8751d53e7d7617", "question": "The original \"Mission Impossible\" TV series ran for how many seasons?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c92e", "question": "Where in the body would you find the malleus, incus and stapes?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d79", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Saga of an American Family\"?", "answer": "Roots", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a3", "question": "Which state is located on the northern border of Pennsylvania?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b6", "question": "Who became \"king of the cowboys\" when Gene Autry entered the army in WWII?", "answer": "Roy Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339859", "question": "In \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Sophie tells Howl that Calcifer hired her as a what?", "answer": "Cleaning lady", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe36e750ada16518afdc045", "question": "What city has traffic lights shaped like Hershey's Kisses?", "answer": "Hershey, Pennsylvania", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51d1fff04d658268c9322", "question": "The world's first postage stamp was introduced in what year?", "answer": "The world's first postage stamp, which featured a portrait of Queen Victoria, was introduced by Great Britain in 1840.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f025ff048f679a45aa97", "question": "Philematophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Kissing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1c", "question": "What name did Superman have on Krypton?", "answer": "Kal-El", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a21f", "question": "What is the name of Jonny Quest's dog?", "answer": "Bandit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067efeff9c0647b50a8080", "question": "What actor played the role of Dr. Frederick Frankenstein in the 1974 film \"Young Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac5", "question": "What year was National Geographic magazine first published?", "answer": "1888", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc5e5ec223966ae8f8884", "question": "Infamous English prisoner, Charles Bronson, was played by what actor in the 2008 film \"Bronson\"?", "answer": "Tom Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774232284458f1d785441e", "question": "What church in Georgia has produced the films \"Flywheel\", \"Facing the Giants\", \"Fireproof\", \"Courageous\",and \"War Room\"?", "answer": "Sherwood Baptist Church, Albany, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33b", "question": "Which 1980's song includes the lyric \"Creatures crawl in search of blood. To terrorize y'alls neighborhood!\"?", "answer": "Thriller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8dd", "question": "The Yellow River is what country's second longest?", "answer": "China's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a97dc61d1b4d384d5d689", "question": "In mythology which giant made of bronze guarded Europa of Crete?", "answer": "Talos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2581931a458464a93c464", "question": "What is a bonbonni\u00e8re?", "answer": "A fancy box or dish used to hold bonbons.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4a997d61d1b4d384d5d69b", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" transition from a Black and White format to a Color format?", "answer": "1966", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b089", "question": "When was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "April 24, 1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c040", "question": "What is a group of Oxen called?", "answer": "Yoke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aac", "question": "What actress played Jane in the 2005 remake of the movie \"Fun with Dick and Jane\"?", "answer": "Tea Leoni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5f", "question": "\"Typo\" is short for what two-word term?", "answer": "Typographical error", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea57b24f84e0b9f9ffd3", "question": "What is the fear of worms, especially parasitic ones, known as?", "answer": "Scoleciphobia, helminthophobia or vermiphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589675db0d66a186cb54b", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c399", "question": "An \"atomizer\" is a device most often used to distribute what?", "answer": "Perfume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd9fbec223966ae8f88e5", "question": "What is the longest movie ever made?", "answer": "Logistics (51,420 minutes long)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30f", "question": "Who sang the 1979 song \"Family Tradition\"?", "answer": "Hank Williams Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f10a9a72b906b34e3d00", "question": "How is sodium bicarbonate better known?", "answer": "Baking soda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c8", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Prions?", "answer": "Stanley Prusiner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ca", "question": "For what crime was Bruno Hauptmann executed in 1936?", "answer": "Kidnapping the Lindbergh baby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb6", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Caribou Lodge\" fraternity?", "answer": "Everybody Loves Raymond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c89e24011619dd6d41548b", "question": "In season 16 of South Park, what chain store did Randy buy for $10,000?", "answer": "Blockbuster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a40", "question": "In 2000, the Black Crowes released a live album recorded with what legendary guitar player?", "answer": "Jimmy Page", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be05", "question": "What \"mocktail\" can be mixed from cranberry and grapefruit juice and peach nectar?", "answer": "Safe sex on the beach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11f", "question": "The first significant gold rush in the US occurred in what state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69c", "question": "Syncope is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902f", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Vulcan?", "answer": "Hephaestos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa1", "question": "What TV show's cops operate out of a converted church they call \"the Barn\"?", "answer": "The Shield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb55", "question": "Who was the first African-American player inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Jackie Robinson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f30", "question": "What literary locale is called \"Manor Farm\" at the start of the novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3e97c73aa70ea0b70af8", "question": "What was the first European name for Hawaii?", "answer": "Captain James Cook, the first European to visit the islands, named them \"the Sandwich islands\" to honor the Earl of Sandwich.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b9", "question": "About whose sister is John Lennon's song \"Dear Prudence\"?", "answer": "Mia Farrow's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90b", "question": "In 2009 what did the \"Sears Tower\" had its name changed to?", "answer": "Willis Tower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a84a", "question": "In what year did Atlanta become the fifth capital of Georgia?", "answer": "1868", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22f", "question": "In 1641, who married Mary Stuart, the daughter of England's King Charles I?", "answer": "William of Orange", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b32349ebf195a31e15d73a7", "question": "Who played the mermaid Madison in the 1984 film \"Splash\"?", "answer": "Daryl Hannah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1bb", "question": "At the 1996 Olympics, what American tied Mark Spitz's lifetime record of nine golds?", "answer": "Carl Lewis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb11", "question": "What early arcade game used a trackball rather than a joystick?", "answer": "Missile Command", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ec", "question": "What is the only breed of cat that does not have retractable claws?", "answer": "The cheetah", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2db", "question": "What was actor Stan Laurel's birth name?", "answer": "Arthur Stanley Jefferson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a295", "question": "Who is Joely Richardson's famous mother?\u00a0", "answer": "Vanessa Redgrave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c990", "question": "Which Russian scientist used dogs to study conditioned reflexes?", "answer": "Ivan Pavlov", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb55c65ff7d326b622a91", "question": "In Shakespeare's play \"Titus Andronicus\", who is the Queen of the Goths?", "answer": "Tamora", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b443", "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick better known as?", "answer": "Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a171", "question": "What is the name of Marty's band in the film \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "The Pinheads", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be5806d5415ba52ed6f0ab4", "question": "Saint Stephen's Day is better known as what?", "answer": "Boxing day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b392", "question": "In what country did the \"Sepoy Mutiny\" occur?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957f", "question": "Renee Zellwegger played Lucy Hil in what 2009 comedy movie?", "answer": "New in Town", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde527ec6c6b019850c9a96", "question": "What type of government ruled Italy during World War II?", "answer": "Fascist", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a263", "question": "Alanis Morrisette appeared on what 1980's TV show?\u00a0", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecca43ec223966ae8f8898", "question": "Paul D. Hubbard is the quarterback who is credited with inventing the modern huddle. What affliction did he suffer from?", "answer": "He was deaf and created the huddle so that he can hear teammates better and hide plays from the defending squad.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b63a01dd7bf43be5e7d7", "question": "Dandelions get their name from what part of a lion?", "answer": "Teeth", "category": "general"}]